MERRICK SAPSFORD

Manchester, England

Mobile Software Engineer I am an experienced software engineer who is primarily focused on development for iOS and associated Apple platforms. The bulk of my experience is in client UI level development, including Auto & manual layout, CoreGraphics and CoreAnimation; however I have also implemented application internals and frameworks.

Experience

Apadmi / Aug 2015 - Present

Software Engineer - Worked as part of the mobile development team at Apadmi to create innovative mobile experiences for a variety of clients. Part of the development team on the BBC Music iOS application; I was responsible for the majority of UI/UX components including complex collection view layouts and CoreGraphics work.

Vulcan to the Sky Trust / March 2011 - Oct 2015

Lead Software Engineer - Responsible for the development of the iOS and Android applications for the last flying Avro Vulcan, XH558. The aircraft was restored to flight in 2007, and flew for a further 9 years until final retirement in 2015. The mobile application was developed and maintained on a charitable basis, featuring a bespoke flight tracking system and comprehensive media library.

AviationLogic / Aug 2013 - July 2014

Lead Software Engineer - I was contracted to design and develop a suite of iOS applications to be used by general aviation pilots, ApproNavigator. The apps provide a dynamic animation canvas built to aid aviators in the planning and execution of an approach to an airfield. The project was particularly challenging due to the complex nature of its intended usage and the responsibility that it entailed.

Evolution Time Critical / Aug 2012 - Feb 2013

Lead Software Engineer - I designed and developed the mobile clients for Evolution Time Critical, an emergency express haulage firm; on iOS, Android and also Windows Phone.

Other

- Computer Science Lab Demonstrator - University of Hull

Skills

- Skilled in Objective-C.
- Proficient in C#, Swift.
- Highly knowledgable of various iOS frameworks.
- Experienced with source control systems (inc. Continuous Integration and Deployment).
- Background with cloud services including MS Azure & Parse.

Education

BSc Computer Software Development (First Class with Honours)

July 2015 - University of Hull

Other

Three A-levels, seventeen GCSE's.

Related Apps

<u>ApproBASE</u> - Circuit Pattern Calculator for GA Pilots.

ApproNAV - Advanced Circuit Pattern Join Calculator for GA Pilots.

BBC Music - Enjoy a personalised slice of BBC Music on your iPhone and iPad.

Contact

<u>merrick@sapsford.tech</u> <u>www.sapsford.tech</u>